Pranesh Santikellur

Personal Information

PHONE: (91) 9886949575 https://bit.ly/2LXi0u2 GOOGLE SCHOLAR:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/praneshss LINKEDIN:

pra.net061@gmail.com, pranesh.sklr@iitkgp.ac.in E-MAIL:

PROFILE

PH.D. SCHOLAR

Currently, I am pursuing a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) degree at the Department of Computer Science, Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur, under the supervision of Professor Rajat Subhra Chakraborty. My research interests are in solving hardware security challenges using machine learning techniques. Prior to joining IIT Kharagpur to pursue my PhD, I worked as an Embedded Linux Developer at Bengaluru, India for nearly 6 years.

EDUCATION

JULY 2017 - PRESENT Ph.D. Research Scholar, Department of Computer Science and Engi-

neering, Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur

AUGUST 2006 - MAY 2010 Bachelor of Engineering, Department of Computer Science, SDM Col-

lege of Engineering and Technology, Dharwad

Percentage: 73.76

Higher Secondary (+2), Karnataka State Board JULY 2004 - MARCH 2006

Percentage: 83.6

JULY 2003 - MARCH 2004 Class X, Karnataka State Board

Percentage: 86.88

WORK EXPERIENCE

SEP 2016 - APR 2020 Senior Research Fellow (SRF).

> I was part of a research project sponsored by Intel USA, entitled "Verification Challenges in Compression and Cryptographic Stacks in Quick-Assist Technology" and worked under the guidance of Dr. Rajat Subhra Chakraborthy. This included analysis of data compression efficiency on

QAT hardware.

DEC 2012 - SEP 2016 Firmware Engineer

> I was part of firmware design team at Horner Engineering Automation Group, Bengaluru, India. My responsibilities were:

- Ported the PLC product code-base from Linux Target Image Builder (LTIB) to Yocto for the new product.
- Developed the touch driver and implemented 3-point calibration rule to it.
- Involved in board bringing up of PLC products with Linux as embedded OS.

SEP 2010 - DEC 2012

Design Engineer

I was part of embedded software team at *Processor Systems Pvt Ltd*, Bengaluru, India. The project was to build the control card for medical application. The tool used for the project were Nios-II Embedded processor. My responsibilities were

 Build the interactive terminal between soft-core MCU unit present inside Nios-II and computer through serial communication. This was also mainly used to download the firmware to flash.

PUBLICATIONS

Воок

P. Santikellur and R. S. Chakraborty, "Deep Learning for Computational Problems in Hardware Security: Modeling Attacks on Strong Physically Unclonable Function Circuits", Springer (forthcoming)

Journals

- **P. Santikellur** and R.S Chakraborty, "Intrinsic Dimension: A Deep Learning Assisted Empirical Metric to Estimate the Robustness of Physically Unclonable Functions to Modeling Attacks" submitted to *IEEE Transactions on Computer-Aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems*.
- S. Chattaopadhyay, **P. Santikellur**, R. S. Chakraborty, J. Mathew and M. Ottavi, "A Conditionally Chaotic Physically Unclonable Function Design Framework with High Reliability", accepted in *ACM Transactions on Design Automation of Electronic Systems*, Apr. 2021.
- **P. Santikellur** and R. S. Chakraborty, "A Computationally Efficient Tensor Regression Network based Modeling Attack on XOR Arbiter PUF and its Variants" *IEEE Transactions on Computer-Aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems.*, doi: 10.1109/TCAD.2020.3032624, Oct. 2020

V. Govindan, R. S. Chakraborty, **P. Santikellur.**, A.K Chandhary, "A Hardware Trojan Attack on FPGA based Cryptographic Key Generation: Impact and Detection", *Journal of Hardware and Systems Security* (Springer), vol. 2, no. 3, pp. 225-239, Sep. 2018.

BOOK CHAPTER

P. Santikellur, R. S. Chakraborty, and J. Mathew, "Hardware Security in the Context of Internet of Things: Challenges and Opportunities." *Internet of Things and Secure Smart Environments: Successes and Pitfalls*, p.299.

CONFERENCES

- P. Santikellur, R. Mukherjee and R. S. Chakraborty, "APUF-BNN: An Automated Framework for Efficient Combinational Logic Based Implementation of Arbiter PUF through Binarized Neural Network,", accepted in 31st ACM Great Lakes Symposium on VLSI (GLSVLSI), Apr. 2021.
- **P. Santikellur**, Lakshya, S. R. Prakash and R. S. Chakraborty, "A Computationally Efficient Tensor Regression Network based Modeling Attack on XOR Arbiter PUF", *IEEE Asian Hardware Oriented Security and Trust Symposium(AsianHOST)*, Xi'an, P.R. China, 2019.
- V. S. Balijabudda, D. Thapar, **P. Santikellur**, R. S. Chakraborty and I. Chakrabarti, "Design of a Chaotic Oscillator based Model Building Attack Resistant Arbiter PUF", *IEEE Asian Hardware Oriented Security and Trust Symposium (AsianHOST)*, Xi'an, China, 2019.
- U. Chatterjee, **P. Santikellur**, R. Sadhukhan, V. Govindan, D. Mukhopadhyay and R. S. Chakraborty, "United We Stand: A Threshold Signature Scheme for Identifying Outliers in PLCs (poster with 2 page short-paper)", Late Breaking Results (LBR) track of *IEEE/ACM Design Automation Conference (DAC)*, Las Vegas, Nevada, USA, 2019.
- **P. Santikellur**, R. Mukherjee, and R. S. Chakraborty: Logic Synthesis of Arbiter PUF using Binarized Neural Networks (poster)", *International Conference on Security, Privacy and Applied Cryptographic Engineering* (SPACE), Gandhinagar, India, 2019.

STUDENT PROJECT

P. Santikellur, T. Haque, M. Al-Zewairi and R. S. Chakraborty, "Optimized Multi - Layer Hierarchical Network Intrusion Detection System with Genetic Algorithms," *IEEE International Conference on new Trends in Computing Sciences (ICTCS)*, Amman, Jordan, 2019.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Intel AI Student Ambassador from IIT Kharagpur, India.
- Intel's one of the first Certified Instructors for oneAPI and DPC++ Essentials.
- Secured Second Prize in CSAW'17 Embedded Security Challenge held at IIT Kanpur, 2017.

INVITED TALKS

- Invited for talk at IIEST, Shibpur on for the topic ""Recent Advances in Machine Learning based Modeling Attacks on PUF".
- Invited for talk at IEEE TENCON 2019 for the topic "Physically Unclonable Functions: Design, Applications, Threats".

TEACHING ASSISTANCE

- Machine learning (CS60050)
- Computer Organisation and Architecture Laboratory (CS39001, CS31007)
- Programming and Data Structures Laboratory (CS11001)

TECHNICAL SKILL

• LANGUAGES: C, C++, MATLAB, PYTHON, VERILOG

• ML FRAMEWORKS: TENSORFLOW(+KERAS), H2O, SCIKIT-LEARN

• TOOLS: LTIB, YOCTO, LATEX, GDB

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

• Co-Chair of ISQED 2021 (Session Title: Application of AI/ML in Hardware Security)

• A member of TCHES 2021 artifact review committee.

• External Reviewer: IEEE TCAD, IEEE TCAS, ACM CSUR, DSD, GLSVLSI, VDAT

REFERENCES

• Prof. Rajat Subhra Chakraborty

Associate Porfessor,

Dept of Computer Science and Engg, IIT Kharagpur, India.

Email: rschakraborty@cse.iitkgp.ac.in

Varsha Chakraborty

Operations Head, Horner Engineering India,

Bengaluru, India.

Email: varsha.chakraborty@india.horner-apg.com